{
  "reference_number": "12611",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": "The Government sets a 2050 target in legislation now",
      "answer_index": 0,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": "Net Zero Long-Lived Gases and Stabilised Short-Lived Gases - Long-lived gases to net zero by 2050 while also stabilising short-lived gases",
      "answer_index": 12,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": "Domestic emissions reductions only (including from new forest planting)",
      "answer_index": 7,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "Yes - the third emissions budget should be able to be changed but only when the subsequent budget is set",
      "answer_index": 4,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Often times Environmental and Climate Change policy is neglected among major political parties due to the benefits of the policy only\n taking effect in the distant future. Governing bodies should optimistically plan to achieve the 2050 goal by implementing short term\n\n goals in which the benefits are foreseeable within a given election cycle(s)."
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Policy and planning needs to be holistic. All ministries and departments need to develop the common interest to introduce policy to\n\ncombat climate change."
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "There is a clear divide between how the environment should be valued between New Zealanders. This is reflected in the varying\nattitudes that individual MPs and Ministers have towards specific Environmental and Climate Change policies. In order to successfully\n\nreach the goal of being carbon neutral by 2050, it is absolutely necessary that the philosophy of sustainability is integrated into every\nMinistry and Department. If the introduction to Climate Change legislation is not introduced holistically, there may be a possible risk of\n\nconflicting ideology between the Climate Change Commission and other government entities. Progressing towards a carbon neutral\neconomy is highly beneficial towards contemporary New Zealand society. With untouched natural landscapes as the main attraction,\n\ntourism is one of the largest industries in New Zealand. There is a significant importance towards the Government to endorse the\nmost up to date Environmental Policy in order to maintain the quality of destinations to both domestic and international visitors.\nEradicating the dependence on a fossil fuel economy will also allow greater national self sufficiency, and localised industries. This is\n\nhighly important for an isolated country developing in an economy with ever diminishing resources."
    }
  ]
}
